# Adam Juraszek



adam.a.juraszek@googlemail.com

https://github.com/crawdaddie

Backend engineer with 6 years of experience passionate about experimentation and clean solutions.

I work closely with product stakeholders to ensure alignment with user needs, and try to learn as much as possible from every member of a team I work with, while pushing for high technical standards from myself and colleagues. I am most interested in roles where I can build on my technical leadership, and work on distributed, data-intesive systems.



### **Experience**

### Curation Corporation - Senior backend developer

London - 6/2021 - present

- Development of internal tools which support ESG experts in synthesising business intelligence from a wide variety of news sources
- designed and implemented backend services for creating automated email briefings which helped reduce the time taken to create briefings by 84% compared to previous non-integrated workflows
- maintenance and tuning of data pipelines which process up to 300,000 articles a day and push them to different search indices
- productionisation and deployment of NLP models as FastAPI services for purposes of abstractive summarisation and entity extraction
- implemented several DX improvements:
  - introduced typescript, and instances of dependency injection
  - increased test-coverage and added backend test-suites to CI pipelines
  - · utilities for repeatable fully-seeded test deployments, and database migrations
  - optimisation and parallelisation of CI/CD pipelines
  - which improved confidence in delivery, code quality and cadence

## Birdie - Full-stack developer

London - 11/2019 - 2/2021

- Development of various frontend and backend components of Birdie's elderly care software ecosystem
- improved performance of backend services by adding permissions-caching layers
- helped improve system consistency by implementing utilities for optimistic concurrency control

# Vectary - 3D developer

Bratislava - 06/2019 - 10/2019

- Refactoring and development of Vectary's 3D-modelling engine (typescript and THREE.js)
- $\bullet$  making detailed optimisations for browser performance through extensive use of the v8 profiler
- responsible for building robust importer/exporter tools for proprietary 3D file formats

# Subdigital - software developer

Bratislava - 08/2018 - 06/2019

- Design and development of hardware (microcontrollers & raspberry pi) & software components of digitally-enhanced architectural models and installations
- building prototypes that helped Subdigital develop new clients
- · mathematical modelling to optimise custom tools in Grasshopper for Rhino

### Lab.SNG - software developer

Bratislava - 01/2018 - 06/2019

- Development of the web-umenia search API for the archives of the Slovak National Gallery
- introduced Docker to team workflow

# Kiwi.com - Junior Python Developer

Bratislava - 11/2016 - 12/2017

• Development of internal HR software using Django

### **Education**

# Institute of Sonology, Koninklijk Conservatorium

MMuc

Den Haag - 2014 - 2016

- Studied music computing, design and development of software synthesis and music performance systems, history and theory of algorithmic music and sound studies
- gave many concerts of my own music using self-built tools

## One Year Cursus

Den Haag - 2013 - 2014

• Music technology and programming for music

# Imperial College - B.Sc Math

• Final year specialism in Topology

London - 2007 - 2010

Skills

#### High Fluency

- Typescript, Node.js, NestJS
- Python, FastApi
- graphql
- PostgreSQL, SQL Server
- kubernetes, Docker
- ElasticSearch
- React

### Intermediate Fluency

- AWS
- Flask, numpy
- HTML, CSS

#### **Side Interests**

- SuperCollider, Max/MSP, audio programming
- Rust, Go

#### **Selected Projects**

- constraint problem solver gui (Octeract, London -2/2021 - 6/2021)
  - python environments which offer interactive solving of MINLP problems using Octeract's libraries
- browser development environment and REPL communicating with python environments over websockets
- Supercollider tools
- project framework for algorithmic composition
- missing import statement
- gui event sequencer
- Múzeum Slovenských národných rád, Myjava -03/2019 Audio installation with ultrasonic distance sensors and arduino microcontrollers
- Keys, Trauma Bar und Kino, Berlin - 02/2019 Live-coding music performance at algorave
- Pohoda Klub stage, Trenčín - 06/2018 Live music performance at a major Slovak music festival